A Guide to the Papers of K. Edward Lay
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Architectural Drawings, Historical American Buildings Survey
  - Cove Church, Covesville (8 sheets) 1978 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - First Presbyterian Church of Niobrara, Niobrara, Knox County, Nebraska (4 sheets) 1977 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Garth Chapel, Owensville (5 sheets) 1981 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Grace Episcopal Church, Cumberland County (6 sheets) - 2 sets n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Mount Ed Baptist Church, Batesville (7 sheets) - 2 sets 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Old Zion Baptist Church (5 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Presbyterian Church, Scottsville (7 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Chapel, Louisa County, north elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Chapel, Louisa County, west elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Chapel, Louisa County, plan n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Chapel, Louisa County, section n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Chapel, Louisa County (7 sheets) 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Church, Scottsville, east elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Church, Scottsville, south elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Church, Scottsville (6 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. John's Church, Waldrop, Louisa County (5 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - St. Luke's Chapel, Simeon (5 sheets) 1981 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Scottsville Disciples of Christ Church (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - South Plains Presbyterian Church (7 sheets) 1984 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Waterford School, Loudoun County (4 sheets) 1979 (Box Oversize Box T-20)
  - Woolen Mills Chapel, Charlottesville (6 sheets) - 2 sets n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-20)
- Architectural Drawings, Historical American Buildings Survey
  - Dwellings: 1973-1983 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Birdwood Ice House (5 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Blenheim Library (8 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Brown-Parrott House, Crozet (11 sheets) 1978 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Walter Coles House, (Old Woodville) (5 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - The Company House, Alberene, northwest elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - The Company House, Alberene, northeast elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - The Company House, Alberene, southwest elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - The Company House, Alberene, southeast elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - The Company House, Alberene (8 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Darby's Folly, Charlottesville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Enniscorthy (5 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Benjamin Harris House, (Mountain Grove) (9 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - James W. Mason House, (Old Hall) (6 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Mills House, (Oaklands; Malvern) (6 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Morven Lawn Cottage, east elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Morven Lawn Cottage, south elevation n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Morven Lawn Cottage (7 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Redlands (6 sheets) (3 sets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Daniel Scott House, (Valmont), Scottsville (7 sheets) (3 sets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - John Scott House, (Mount Walla), Scottsville (8 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Solitude (8 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Sowell House, Scottsville (5 sheets) 1979 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Spring Hill Claim House (5 sheets) 1978 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Springdale Farm (7 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Sunny Bank (7 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Walters-Page House, Batesville (10 sheets) (2 sets) 1974 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Wilhoit House (10 sheets) (2 sets) 1973 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Other Buildings: 1977-1979 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - C & O Railway Station, Shadwell (5 sheets) 1979 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - C & O Railway Station, Scottsville (6 sheets) 1977 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Crossroads Tavern (10 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - George Lodge 32, Howardsville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Hatton Grange Mill, Hatton (8 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - J. I. Maupin Store (2 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - J. I. Maupin Store (10 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Stockton Creek Barn, Greenwood (4 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Stockton Creek Barn, Greenwood (13 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Sutherland Barn (7 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-21)
  - Warren Depot (7 sheets) n.d (Box Oversize Box T-21)
- Architectural Drawings, Historical American Buildings Survey
  - Dwellings: 1974-1993 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Aspendale, Kent County, Delaware (5 sheets) 1975 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Barclay House, Scottsville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Belleville, Ware Neck, Gloucester County (7 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Blair House, (Tipton Blair House), Scottsville (9 sheets) 1993 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Blum House, Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana (4 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Edward Coles House, Nelson County (6 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - One Cottage Lane, Charlottesville (7 sheets) 1974 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Lucretia Cox House, Staunton, Augusta (4 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - 117 Cream Street, Charlottesville (5 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Charles B. Dudley House, Altoona, Blair, Pennsylvania (5 sheets) 1989 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Fowler House, Charlottesville (7 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Carter Gilmer House, Charlottesville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Hughes House, Charlottesville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Jeffries-Bruce House, Scottsville (8 sheets) 1990 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Locust Grove, Greene County (8 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Locust Grove Kitchen, Charlottesville (6 sheets) 1981 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - 1901 E. Market Street (6 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Norris-Preston Cottage, Charlottesville (5 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Price-Poore House, Charlottesville (7 sheets) 1993 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Snow Hill, (Colonel Samuel Booth), Surry County (10 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Spring Grove, Westmoreland County (8 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - 104 Twelfth Street, Charlottesville (6 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Vowles Townhouses, Charlottesville (10 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Judge Watson House (8 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - 1213 West Main Street, Charlottesville (5 sheets) 1983 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - John Winn House, Belmont, Charlottesville (12 sheets) 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - John Winn House, Belmont, Charlottesville (8 sheets) 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, details (2 sets) 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, section 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, northeast elevation 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, northwest elevation 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, southeast elevation 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County, southwest elevation 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Woodlawn, Essex County (12 sheets) 1976 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Other Buildings: 19-- (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Albemarle County Courthouse, Charlottesville (6 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Canal Warehouse, Scottsville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - 220 Court Square, Charlottesville (5 sheets) 1982 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Fork Union Depot, Fluvanna County (6 sheets) 1978 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Fry's Spring Filling Station, Charlottesville (4 sheets) 1981 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Inge's Store, Charlottesville (8 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Ionia Barn, Green Springs, Louisa County (6 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Old A. J. Long Mill, Greene County (5 sheets) (2 sets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Montpelier Depot, Orange County (9 sheets) 1977 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Norris-McCue Building, Charlottesville (9 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Piedmont Log House, Orange County (3 sheets) n.d. (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Pleasant Valley Depot, Rockingham County, principal elevation 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Pleasant Valley Depot, Rockingham County, section and side elevation 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Pleasant Valley Depot, Rockingham County (5 sheets) 1986 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
  - Redwood Ordinary, Williamsburg, James City County (3 sheets) 1981 (Box Oversize Box T-22)
- Architectural Drawings, Historical American Buildings Survey
  - Pavilion III at the University of Virginia (3 sheets) n.d. (Folder Folder 1: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Pavilion VI at the University of Virginia (12 sheets) 1990 (Folder Folder 1: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Pavilion VII at the University of Virginia (5 sheets) 1990 (Folder Folder 1: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Pavilion IX at the University of Virginia (19 sheets) n.d. (Folder Folder 1: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Hotel "B" at the University of Virginia 1961-1962 (Folder Folder 2: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Albemarle County Court House 1961-1963 (Folder Folder 3: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Barboursville Ruins (6 sheets) 1981 (Folder Folder 3: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Edward Coles House, Greenfield, Nelson County (6 sheets) 1983 (Folder Folder 4: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Walter Coles House, (Old Woodville), Esmont (5 sheets) 1983 (Folder Folder 4: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Enniscorthy, Keene (5 sheets) 1982 (Folder Folder 4: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Redlands, Carter's Bridge (6 sheets) 1982 (Folder Folder 4: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Blenheim (2 sheets) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - John A. G. Davis House, (The Farm), Charlottesville (9 sheets) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Market Hall, Charleston, South Carolina (1 sheet) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Noland-Haukenberry House, Independence, Missouri (1 sheet) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Prestwould Slave Quarters, Clarksville, Mecklenburg County (2 sheets) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Sands & Company Hotel Building, Monroe 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - George Wallace House, Independence, Missouri (1 sheet) 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Old Woodville, Esmont 19-- (Folder Folder 5: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Tallwood, Green Mountain Road (5 sheets) (3 sets) and measured pencil drawings (4 sheets) 1981 (Folder Folder 6: Oversize Tray 242)
  - D. S. Tavern (5 sheets) n.d. (Folder Folder 7: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Gadsby's Tavern, Alexandria (36 sheets) 1988-1992 (Folder Folder 7: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Southern Railway Depots (22 sheets) n.d. (Folder Folder 8: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Masonic Temple, Altoona, Blair County, Pennsylvania (2 sheets) 1989 (Folder Folder 9: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Cambria Iron Company, Cambria County, Pennsylvania (30 sheets) 1988 (Folder Folder 10: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Mount Etna Iron Works, Blair County, Pennsylvania (24 sheets) 1988 (Folder Folder 11: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Various Styles of Buildings 1991-1992 (Folder Folder 12: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Site Plans and Plats of Charlottesville, University of Virginia, and others n.d. (Folder Folder 13: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Maps and Plats of Virginia Counties n.d. (Folder Folder 14: Oversize Tray 242)
  - U. S. Geological Survey Maps of Virginia Counties 1967-1987 (Folder Folder 15: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Albemarle County Jail #5 (11 sheets) 1995 (Folder Folder 16: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Gadsby's Tavern, Alexandria n.d. (Folder Folder 16: Oversize Tray 242)
  - Plat of Virginia Counties n.d. (Folder Folder 16: Oversize Tray 242)